{
    "id": "73346420e72347778ccd7fef4213ea0c",
    "title": "Tenses In Subordinate Clauses Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "73226200be434ab1a1ebe432ca1d4ea9",
            "title": "Tenses In Subordinate Clauses",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I will lend it to you on condition that you ……………………… it back tomorrow.",
                    "description": "Present tenses are often used instead of will + infinitive to refer to the future in subordinate clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "bring",
                        "will bring",
                        "would bring"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It will be interesting to see whether he …………………………… it or not.",
                    "description": "Present tenses are often used instead of will + infinitive to refer to the future in subordinate clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "completes",
                        "will complete",
                        "would complete"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will call you when I ………………………..",
                    "description": "Present tenses are often used instead of will + infinitive to refer to the future in subordinate clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have finished",
                        "will have finished",
                        "had finished"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t know where I ………………………… tomorrow.",
                    "description": "When the main verb is in the present tense, we use a future tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "am",
                        "would be",
                        "will be"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have bought a chicken in case Peter ……………………………….",
                    "description": "We normally use a present tense with a future meaning after in case.",
                    "answers": [
                        "arrive",
                        "will arrive",
                        "arrives"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "It doesn’t matter where we ………………………… on holiday.",
                    "description": "Present tenses are also used with a future meaning after it doesn’t matter.",
                    "answers": [
                        "go",
                        "went",
                        "will go"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t care what we ……………………….. for dinner as long as I don’t have to cook it.",
                    "description": "Present tenses are also used with a future meaning after I don’t care.",
                    "answers": [
                        "had",
                        "have",
                        "will have",
                        "would have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I asked whether she ………………………… any message for me.",
                    "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we will typically need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has",
                        "had",
                        "will have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We wish that it ……………………….. forever.",
                    "description": "We usually use a past tense after wish to talk about something unreal or unlikely.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will rain",
                        "had rained",
                        "would rain"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I wish tomorrow ………………………… Sunday.",
                    "description": "We usually use a past tense after wish to talk about something unreal or unlikely.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "was",
                        "had been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It’s time the children ……………………….. to bed.",
                    "description": "We use a past tense after it’s time with a present meaning.",
                    "answers": [
                        "went",
                        "go",
                        "have gone"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You had better ……………………… before I call the police.",
                    "description": "We use the infinitive without to after had better.",
                    "answers": [
                        "leave",
                        "left",
                        "to leave"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}